# Caleb Dudley

PHONE |
EMAIL |
WEB |
LINKEDIN

207.200.5052 caleb@calebdudleydesign.com calebdudleydesign.com linkedin.com/in/calebdudley

## **Summary**

Software engineer with 13+ years of experience building clean, scalable web applications that are usable, accessible, and genuinely enjoyable to use. I currently architect and build React/TypeScript applications that balance user empathy with technical excellence. Favorite tools: TypeScript, React, React Router, and React Query/Axios.

#### **Skills**

HTML/CSS • JavaScript/TypeScript • React • React Router • React Query/Axios • Web Accessibility (WCAG) • Webpack Module Federation • Yarn/npm • Git • GitHub • GitHub Actions • CSS Preprocessors (LESS/SCSS) • Photoshop/Illustrator Video Editing (AE/Final Cut) • Sound Editing • Django/Django REST Framework • Python • MySQL

## **Professional Experience**

| Contrast Security   Staff Software Engineer | • | 2021 - | Present |
|---|---|--------|---------|
|---|---|--------|---------|

- Develop, enhance, and maintain user interfaces across the Contrast Security suite of applications, includes monorepos and micro-frontends
  - | TypeScript React React Router React Query/Axios Angular (v1)
- Architected, built, and continue to enhance the front-end foundation of Northstar, Contrast's new customer product for Application Detection & Response
  - | TypeScript React React Router React Query/Axios Pure CSS and emotion/css
- Collaborate with UX and Product to define requirements for reusable components (WCAG 2 AA compliant), styles, and
  patterns for our in-house design system
  | TypeScript \* React \* emotion/css \* Storybook
- Lead migration of legacy features to React-based applications, improving performance and consistency across the platform | TypeScript React React Router React Query/Axios emotion/css

## Blackhawk Network, Inc. 2017 – 202

- Developed and maintained business-to-business and consumer gift card/prepaid solutions
- Built Node.js SPAs using a Django REST framework and JavaScript architecture, including Backbone and React
- Scrum Master of a team, working closely with product to help prioritize new features as well as ensure our team has everything needed to deliver on time
- Supported back end Python/Django systems with other experience in SQL (MySQL) and services like Bitbucket, Jenkins, Rally, and Jira

#### CashStar, Inc. 2012 – 2017

- Managed client sites and digital assets, maintained application support for desktop, mobile, and legacy browsers, and provided engineering support for projects
- Onboarded clients to our consumer platform and frequently engaged directly with our customers to receive feedback
- Joined a Scrum team in 2013 that focused on business-to-business solutions and continued through our acquisition by Blackhawk Network in August of 2017

#### FetchDog (Fetch Enterprises, Inc.) 2011 – 2012

- Worked with a small team of designers to create and manage digital content for online products sold at FetchDog.com
- Helped design and schedule promotional email campaigns and assisted in digital marketing of our products

#### Client Attraction 2011

- Maintained the corporate website, additional community websites, and customer database software
- Assisted in online marketing, social media, video editing, print design for corporate events, and helped create other marketing material

### **Certifications**

Certified Scrum Master

#### **Education** | 2007 – 2011

**Lyndon State College** – Lyndonville, VT B.A. Digital Media B.A. Graphic Design

## Interests